Guide to the Wesley H. Greene Papers 1900-1996
University of Chicago Library
Greene, Wesley H. Papers
1900-1996
27.5 linear feet (38 boxes, 2 oversize folders)
Hanna Holborn Gray Special Collections Research Center University of Chicago Library 1100 East 57th Street Chicago, Illinois 60637 U.S.A.
Wesley H. Greene operated a Chicago-based film distributorship, and also worked as an educator, administrator and activist focused on film and the visual arts. His distribution concerns, including International Film Bureau, College Film Center, and Trans-World Films, handled a variety of film genres and served schools, colleges and universities, churches, clubs and businesses. This collection includes records of Greene's film distribution companies; posters and other movie publicity material; records of the Chicago Film Council; programs from Greene's international film series at University of Chicago; records of the Committee to Preserve the Ferguson Fund for Sculpture and Greene's litigation against the Art Institute of Chicago; and personal correspondence and memorabilia.
Information on Use
Access
Series VI includes financial records of the International Film Bureau, and financial records of the Greene family. This material is restricted until 2046.
Series VI also includes medical records. This material is restricted until 2076.
The remainder of the collection is open for research, with no restrictions.
Biographical Note
Wesley Hammond Greene was born in Romney, West Virginia in 1907, and educated at Randolph-Macon College (A.B. 1927) and University of Virginia (A.M. 1929). He began his career in education as a history and social sciences teacher, working in Virginia high schools, Allegheny College, and the University of Chicago's Laboratory Schools.
Through work with the University of Chicago's International House, Greene became interested in film as an educational medium. In 1937, he incorporated International Film Bureau, an importer and exporter of educational films. Greene subsequently created additional branches of his distributorship, including College Film Center, which specialized in low-cost rentals of classroom films, and Trans-World Films, which distributed foreign films and general entertainment titles. Greene's companies handled a variety of film genres, particularly European and Latin American features, art and experimental films, foreign language instruction series, vocational guidance films, and classic entertainment titles. Greene's clients included schools, colleges and universities, churches, clubs and businesses.
In the 1930s, Greene developed film series in coordination with University of Chicago affiliated organizations such as International House, the Renaissance Society, and the University Film Society. During the early 1940s, Greene and his family moved to Canada, where he served on the National Film Board. In Chicago, he was active on the Chicago Film Council, and organized the group's Films of the World Festival in 1947.
In 1957, Greene led the Committee to Preserve the Ferguson Fund for Sculpture in challenging the Art Institute of Chicago's administration of the Benjamin F. Ferguson Fund. Established in 1905 for the development of the Chicago's sculpture and monument collections, the fund had been used by the Art Institute of Chicago for building construction, maintenance and other administrative and operational costs. The committee's efforts culminated in Wesley Greene vs. the Art Institute of Chicago and the Northern Trust Company.
Greene married the artist Marie Zoe Greene-Mercier in 1937; the couple lived in Hyde Park and raised three sons.
Scope Note
Series I: Film Distribution, contains records of Greene's film distribution companies, particularly those of the International Film Bureau and Trans World Films. Much of the material in this series consists of publicity material for films and film distributorships, including catalogs, press books, print advertisements, stills, lobby cards, inserts, clippings, posters and press releases. Also included is correspondence negotiating distribution rights; internal reviews of films; scripts and translations of dialogue; artwork and layouts for catalogs; and files on business and film equipment. This series includes material in German, Spanish, French and Italian.
Series II: Chicago Film Council, includes correspondence, minutes, membership records, programs and announcements, spanning the years 1946-1949. Also included is related material from other regional film councils and their sponsoring organization, the Film Council of America. Greene's work in organizing the 1947 Films of the World Festival is represented in this series.
Series III: University of Chicago, documents campus film series that Greene organized from 1932-1941. Included are programs and publications from series hosted by the University Film Society, International House and the Renaissance Society.
Series IV: Committee to Preserve the Ferguson Fund for Sculpture, includes the group's financial and administrative records, correspondence, publicity material, background research on the Art Institute and the Ferguson Fund, clippings, and records of legal proceedings.
Series V: Personal, includes correspondence, biographical material, yearbooks, maps and other travel material, political material, periodicals and clippings. Several unidentified files containing notes, correspondence, periodicals, clippings and publicity material are included at the end of the series.
Series VI: Restricted, contains financial records of International Film Bureau, as well as personal financial and medical records.
Related Resources
The following related resources are located in the Department of Special Collections:
http://www.lib.uchicago.edu/e/spcl/select.html
Marie Zoe Greene-Mercier. Papers
Charles Benton. Papers
William Benton. Papers
Subject Headings
Greene, Wesley H.; Art Institute of Chicago; Chicago Film Council; International Film Bureau, Inc.; International House (Chicago, Ill.); National Film Board of Canada; Trans-World Films; Educational films; Film festivals; Film posters; Foreign films; Language and languages -- Study and teaching; Motion picture industry; Motion pictures -- Distribution; Motion pictures -- Marketing; Motion pictures in education; Visual education
INVENTORY
- Series I: Film Distribution
  This series contains records of Greene's film distribution companies, particularly those of the International Film Bureau and Trans World Films. Much of the material in this series consists of publicity material for films and film distributorships, including catalogs, press books, print advertisements, stills, lobby cards, inserts, clippings, posters and press releases. German films of the 1930s are particularly well represented in this series, as are Mexican and other Spanish-language films of the 1930s-1950s. Also included is correspondence negotiating distribution rights; internal reviews of films; scripts and translations of dialogue; artwork and layouts for catalogs; and files on business and film equipment.
  Dates given in the inventory are for the materials contained in the file, and do not document the release dates of films.
  Subseries 1: Subject File, includes files organized alphabetically. Administrative records are usually filed by business name ("International Film Bureau" or "Trans-World Films"). Other typical subjects include the names of clients, vendors, products, films and film genres. Unidentified files are collected at the end of this subseries.
  Subseries 2: Movie Posters and Oversize Publicity Material, contains print material such as large posters, press books, lobby cards, inserts and photographs. Also included is a set of English subtitle cards, circa 1950s-1960s, for the 1931 production of Brothers Karamazov. Material in this subseries is organized by size, then alphabetically by subject.
  Restricted material from this series has been transferred to Series VI.
  - Subseries 1: Subject File
    - Adventures of Chico, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Alaska, 1950-1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Alexandroff, Leon, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Alice in Wonderland, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Altura Films, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - André und Ursula, circa 1955 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Ansel Adams: Photographer, circa 1960s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Apollo Pictures, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Army Pictorial Service, 1943 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Arsenic and Old Lace, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Associated British-Pathe Limited, circa 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Audio Film Center, 1950-1963 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Australian National Film Board, circa 1945 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Automobile safety films, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Azteca Films, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 1, Folder 15-16)
    - Bailey Films, Inc., 1954-1956 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Basketball films, 1946-1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Bauhaus-Archiv, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Betty Crocker Method of Making Cake, circa 1950s (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Berlin wie sie war, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Biology films, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Birth of a Nation, 1952-1965 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Bolero, 1935 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Bookkeeping and accounting equipment, circa 1930s-1940s (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Boulton-Hawker Films, Ltd., 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Britain's Countryside, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - British Film Institute, 1934-1940 (Box 2, Folder 8-11)
    - British Film Institute, 1940-1957 (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
    - British films, 1933-1963 (Box 3, Folder 4-9)
    - British Information Services, 1945-1948 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - British Information Services, 1952-1958 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - British transport films, 1952-1963 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Bulb Changer, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Brothers Karamazov, 1931-1954 (Box 4, Folder 5-6)
    - Calvin Productions, Inc., 1969 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Cameras, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Canada, 1945-1974 (Box 4, Folder 9-12)
    - Canadian consulate, circa 1950s (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Canadian Education Showplace, 1969-1974 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Canadian Orienteering Services, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Canadian travel films, 1952-1961 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Canadian Films Reviewed, 1939-1941 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Canadian Wheat Story, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Canals of England, 1938-1951 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Canyon Cinema Cooperative, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1950 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Carnival in Flanders, circa 1936 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Cartridge Cassette Commander, circa 1970s (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Casa Colorada, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Castle Films, 1947-1955 (Box 5, Folder 13-14)
    - Cathedral Films, circa 1953 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Cattle Country, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - La Caza, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Censorship: A Question of Judgment, 1963-1965 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Central Africa, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Central States Modern Language Teachers Association, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Centre National de Documentation Pedagogique, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Certified for Seed, 1945-1949 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Chemistry films, circa 1960s (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Chicago Board of Education, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Chicago Metro History Fair, 1991 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Children of Paradise, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Children and their Pictures, 1955 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Children's Charter, undated (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Children's series, 1954-1963 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Christmas programming, 1937-1950 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Chroniques de France, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Cine World, Inc., 1977-1978 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Cinema Français, 1980 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Cinespaña, SA, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - The City, 1939-1956 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Clasa-Mohme, Inc., circa 1950s (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Clasa-Mohme, Inc., circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 1-2)
    - Cohrssen, Hans, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - College Film Center, circa 1930s-1950s (Box 7, Folder 4-5)
    - Columbia Pictures Corporation, 1956-1967 (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
    - Columbia University, 1940-1958 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Czechoslovakian short films, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Department of National Health and Welfare, 1951 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Deren, Maya, 1946-1947 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Dimensions, Inc., 1951 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Doña Perfecta, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Dramatics, 1951-1962 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Earth and Its Peoples, circa 1950s (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Educational Screen, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Elephant Boy, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Equipment, 8-millimeter films, 1960-1965 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Equipment catalogs, circa 1950s (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Erherzog Johanns Grosse Liebe, circa 1950 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - European films, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
    - Faust, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Film Forum Review, 1947 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Film News, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 8, Folder 7-8)
    - Film projection, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Film Quarterly, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Film World, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Filmespaña, 1962 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Films, Inc. 1939-1966 (Box 8, Folder 13-15)
    - "Films for the Study and Enjoyment of Art," circa 1960s (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Focus, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Ford, John, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Foreign Language Review, 1962-1965 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Forêt Secrète d'Afrique, undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Forum Films, 1950-1951 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Français par le Film, circa 1950s (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - France, 1941-1961 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - French film reader series, circa 1960s (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - French films, 1935-1962 (Box 9, Folder 10-11)
    - Gesamtverzeichnis der Wissenschaftlichen Filme, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Georgy Girl, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - German film courses and resources, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - German films, circa 1930s (Box 9, Folder 15-17)
    - Gloria Films, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Golden Demon, 1959-1960 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - The Great Game, 1947 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Greene, Luther, 1953-1977 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
    - Greene-Mercier, Marie Zoe, 1966-1978 (Box 10, Folder 4-5)
    - Gregg-Moore Lithographing Company, circa 1960s-1970s (Box 10, Folder 6-8)
    - Group Discussion Guide, 1940-1941 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - La Guitarra Española, circa 1960s (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Guten Morgen, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Guten Tag, 1974-1983 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Hallo Ostfriesland, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Hamlet, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Harvest, 1939 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Harwald Company, circa 1950s (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - "Health Hazards in Art," circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Ideal Pictures, circa 1960s (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Indiana University, 1955 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - The Innocent, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Interama, 1975 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Interlochen Arts Academy, 1965-1970 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - International Film Bureau, 1944-circa 1980s (Box 11, Folder 11-14)
    - International Film Bureau, catalogs, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 11, Folder 15-16)
    - International Film Bureau, catalogs, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 12, Folder 1-7)
    - International Film Bureau, Equipment Sales Division, circa 1940s- 1950s (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - International Film Bureau, films pending distribution, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - International Film Bureau, news bulletin artwork, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - International Film Bureau, pamphlets, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 13, Folder 1-5)
    - International Film Bureau, 35-millimeter releases, 1946-1984 (Box 13, Folder 6-7)
    - International Harvester Company, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Isola Bella, 1960s (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Les Jeux sont Faits, 1963-1965 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Jordan Valley, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Joseph Brenner Associates, circa 1950s (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Kanku, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Khandhar, 1983 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Labor films, circa 1950s (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Last of the Nomads, circa 1957 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Leases, 1948-1952 (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Library Films, Inc., circa 1930s (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Library prints, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Living City, 1953 (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - La Loire, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Long Filmslide Service, 1962-1963 (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Louis Weiss and Company, circa 1940s (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Macbeth, circa 1940s-1950s (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Madeline, 1952-1964 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Marcelino Pan y Vino, circa 1960s (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Mathematics Teacher, 1962 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Der Maulkorb, circa 1950s (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - McLaren, Norman, 1965-1971 (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Medium, circa 1950s (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Mexican films, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 14, Folder 24-26)
    - Middlebury College, 1965 (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Midwestern Forum on Visual Teaching Aids, 1939-1940 (Box 14, Folder 28-29)
    - Midwestern Forum on Visual Teaching Aids, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Les Misérables, 1952 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Modus Operandi, circa 1960s (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Moore, Henry, 1948 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Movie Surplus Sales, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Music for the Millions, circa 1950s (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Mystic Mountain, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - National Air and Space Administration (NASA), 1963 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - National Arts Education Association, 1957-1959 (Box 15, Folder 9-10)
    - National Children's Film Library, circa 1940s (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - National Film Board of Canada, 1948-1982 (Box 15, Folder 12-15)
    - Near Home, 1947-1951 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Newsweek Educational Bureau, circa 1946 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Nichtenhauser, Adolf, 1945 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Night Train, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Nikkatsu Corporation, 1967-1968 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Now the Peace, 1945 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Oedipus Rex, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Of the End, undated (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - One Potato, Two Potato, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Opvoedkundige Films, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Oresteia, circa 1950s (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Ott, John, 1950-1963 (Box 16, Folder 9-12)
    - Out of Time, 1952 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Outdoor Pictures, 1966 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - "Peliculas Educativas," McGraw-Hill, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - Permits and censoring, 1935-1940 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Philadelphia Art Museum, 1946-1947 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - Philadelphia Story, 1940 (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - Photographer's Catalog, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Physical education and sports films, circa 1960s (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Pictura Films Corporation, 1952-1958 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Portrait of Molière, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - Post Pictures Corporation, 1972 (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - Randolph-Macon Academy, 1942-1953 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Rembrandt, circa 1940s (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - River of Canada, 1944 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Roa's Films, 1956 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Robber Symphony, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Roosevelt Story, 1947-1949 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Round Trip, circa 1948 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Rules of the Game, circa 1939 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Safe at Home, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Safety instruction films, 1976-1977 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Schimmelreiter, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - Schlussakkord, 1936-1937 (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Scholastic Teacher Monthly, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - School Library Journal, 1967 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Seattle Film Festival, 1959 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Second Bureau, 1936-1937 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Shakespeare, 1934-1977 (Box 18, Folder 5-7)
    - Shakespeare's Theater: The Globe Playhouse, 1954 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Short films, 1935-1938 (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Silent Enemy, circa 1930 (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Silent films, circa 1940s-1973 (Box 18, Folder 11-12)
    - Silent Night, Holy Night, circa 1930s (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Sixteen-millimeter films, 1945-1948 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Ski Chase, 1936-1939 (Box 18, Folder 15)
    - Slalom, 1933-1936 (Box 18, Folder 16)
    - Slides, circa 1940s-1960s (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Smile While You Can, circa 1970s (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Society of Motion Picture and Television Engineers, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Song of China, 1937-1964 (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - Song of Freedom, circa 1950s (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Solang' noch untern Linden, circa 1958 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Sorcerer's Apprentice, 1935 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Spain, circa 1940s-1960 (Box 19, Folder 8-10)
    - Spanish-language films, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 19, Folder 11-12)
    - Spanish-language films, 1942-1969 (Box 20, Folder 1-8)
    - Spectre of the Rose, 1946 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Spelunking, 1948 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Splicer Corporation, 1980 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Sport films, 1954-1966 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - St. Francis of Assisi, 1947 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    - The Stevenson Story, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 14)
    - Strangers When They Meet, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 15)
    - Ein Student ging vorbei, circa 1960 (Box 20, Folder 16)
    - Surrealism, 1947-1969 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Swedish films, 1929-1956 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Symphonie Pastorale, 1966 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Tamarelle's International Films, Ltd., 1987 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Tanzendes Holz, circa 1930s (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Target for Tonight, circa 1940s (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - This is My Friend, 1958-1959 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Tierra Mexicana, 1947-1951 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Titan: The Story of Michelangelo, circa 1950-1952 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Today We Live, 1937 (Box 21, Folder 10)
    - Toei, circa 1960s (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Tomorrow is Forever, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Tonio Kroeger, undated (Box 21, Folder 13)
    - Transcanada Express, 1944 (Box 21, Folder 14)
    - Trans-World Films, circa 1920s-1960s (Box 21, Folder 15-19)
    - Trans-World Films, circa 1969-1987 (Box 22, Folder 1-4)
    - Traumulus, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Truxa, circa 1937 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - United States Film Service, 1939 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - United World Films, 1938-1964 (Box 22, Folder 8-9)
    - Vernon J. Kraft Film Productions, 1956 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - V-I, 1944 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Via Mala, circa 1961 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Vocational Guidance Films, Inc., 1940 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Le Voyage Imprevu, circa 1935 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - War films, 1938-1941 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Was die Schalbe sang, circa 1956 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Washington, D.C., 1957-1969 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Wayne State University Press, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Weyerhaeuser, Inc., undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Wide Angle, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Wirtshaus im Spessart, 1958-1967 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Works Progress Administration (WPA) Film Library, circa 1992 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Young Men's Christian Association (YMCA) Motion Picture Bureau, 1934-1946 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Unidentified files, circa 1930s-1980s (Box 23, Folder 7-10)
    - Unidentified files, circa 1930s-1980s (Box 24, Folder 1-4)
  - Subseries 2: Movie Posters and Oversize Publicity Material
    - Brothers Karamazov, circa 1950s-1960s (Box 25)
    - Adventures of Chico, circa 1938 (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Alerte en Méditerranée, circa 1938 (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Barcarole, circa 1935 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Café Colon, circa 1959 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Christine, circa 1937 (Box 26, Folder 5)